Finding Aid for the Nan Britton Papers LSC.0467
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Documentary Files
  - Facsimile of registration of G.H. Harvey & wife, Cleveland, at the Imperial Hotel, New York (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Nan Britton's note: ... facsimile of Mr. Harding's registering of us ...
  - Draft of The President's Daughter, with editorial markings, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Nan Britton's note: ... My carbon copy was subsequently destroyed by me. Also, because of very personal allusions in my statement for Mr. Ashley, the original 'legal' manuscript, writeen for the attorney, was destroyed by me.
  - Draft of Honesty or Politics (original title Stony Limits), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Nan Britton's note: ... many passages were cut out at the suggestion of the critic who viewed it. (Clifton Fadiman)
  - Letter from Lillian Knell to Nan Britton with clippings re Warren G. Harding, June 19, 1926. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Lillian Knell was the niece of Mrs. Jack (Mary) Pusey.
  - School report of Elizabeth Ann Harding (Willits) which appears in The President's Daughter, opposite p.280, June 4, 1925. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Letter (carbon copy) from Nan Britton to the New York Times re permission to use Nan Britton's poem The child's eyes in a forthcoming book and their reply, January 20, January 26, 1920. (Box 2, Folder 17)
    With facsimile of Nan Britton's first check received for the sale of any writing and a clipping of The Times, August 30, 1926 with the printed poem.
  - Letter from Helen Evans to Nan Britton and Nan Britton's reply (carbon copy), November 3 & November 5, 1927. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Helen Evans was Nan Britton's nurse at the time Elizabeth Ann was born.
  - Telegram from Nan Britton to Mrs. Elizabeth Willits re President Harding's death, August 3, 1923. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Nan Britton's note: Elizabeth, her husband and Elizabeth Ann we re visiting Scott Willits' mother and father at the time, at their country home near Keithsburg, Illinois.
  - Postcards of The Claypool Hotel, McFarland Hotel, and Witherill Hotel (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Nan Britton's note: See The President's Daughter, pp.37-39 and 57-60 where these are mentioned.
  - Bankbooks. 4 items, 1919-1921. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Nan Britton's note: ... monies given to me by Mr. Harding ...
  - Campaign poster likeness of President Harding which hung on Nan Britton's bedroom wall, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Reproduced in The President's Daughter, p.12.
  - Letter from Elizabeth Ann to her mother Nan Britton, 1926. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Nan Britton's note: ... (written when she was in 2nd grade ina a Chicago public school). Reproduced in The President's Daughter, p.372.
  - High school senior oration by Nan Britton, notations by Abigail Harding, 1914. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - The autobiography of me by Nan Britton, 1921. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    Written for a class assignment at Columbia University.
  - Today's Health, with A day with Papa by Nan Britton, pp.30-33, 90-91, February 1966. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    Based on a brief sketch in The autobiography of me.
  - At the keyhole of the Cabinet Room, New York Times, June 5, 1921. (Box 3, Folder 10)
    With photocopy. Nan Britton's note: See p.155, 1st paragraph, The President's Daughter.
  - Photograph of Nan Britton holding Elizabeth Ann, 1921. (Box 3, Folder 11)
    See p.164, The President's Daughter.
  - Photographs of Warren G. Harding. 2 items, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Photographs by Harris & Ewing See opposite 164, The President's Daughter.
  - Photograph of Warren G. Harding, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 13)
    See opposite p. 173, The President's Daughter.
  - Photograph of the White House, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 14)
    Photo copyright by Ernest L. Crandall. See p. 156, The President's Daughter.
  - Photographs of the White House. 2 items, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 15)
    Copyright by Ernest L. Crandall. See opposite p. 189, The President's Daughter.
  - Photograph of Warren G. Harding, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 16)
    Copyright by Edmonston Studio, Washington, D.C. Note by Nan Britton: Reprints of other photos or pictures appearing opposite pp.129, 134, 160, 180, 204 in The President's Daughter are in my 'Harding scrapbook.'
  - Manuscript for French translation by Louis Postif of The President's Daughter, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Letter from Harry Winfield Saxton to the Editor of the Boston Post, October 29, 1927. (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Saxton was a member of the Armstrong tour, the group Nan Britton traveled with to Dijon in the summer of 1923. See episode 103, pp.248-249 in The President's Daughter.
  - Letter from Elizabeth Ann to her mother, Nan Britton, September 21, 1927. (Box 3, Folder 19)
    See opposite p. 340 in The President's Daughter.
  - Correspondence of Addison B. Colvin, 1930-1931. (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Re the Harding Memorial Association.
  - Letters re opening of Nan Britton's mail by the Post Office, 1930, 1932, 1933. (Box 3, Folder 21)
    Letter from William Marsteller, November 1, 1930, Nan Britton, October 30, 1930, Nathan Loeser, October 31, 1930, Jessie Conley, March 17, 1932 and Nan Britton's reply, May 3, 1932. 2 letters from Nan Britton's mother, February 1, 1930 and Fall 1930.
  - Letter from office of F.E. Scobey to Nan Britton and Nan Britton's reply and related clipping, September 8 & 12, 1924. (Box 3, Folder 22)
    Clipping is about the death of Frank E. Scobey, 1931.
  - Affidavit of Mrs. Marietta Tonnesen, November 16, 1926. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Affidavit of Helen J. Evans and statement by Nan Britton, October 22, 1919; October 27, 1926. (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Helen J. Evans was nurse to Nan Britton when Elizabeth Ann was born.
  - Letter from Nan Britton to Judge Louis B. McNeal and copy of Warren Harding's last will and testament, January 5, 7, 9, 1928. (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Nan Britton's note: Figures on attached legal-size yellow paper must be those of my attorney, Mr. Kelley.
  - Adverse and semi-adverse reviews and comments, some humorous, on The President's Daughter., 1927-1928. (Box 4, Folder 4-16)
    13 folders. Clippings and preservation photocopies. Duplicates.
  - Favorable and semi-favorable reviews and comments on The President's Daughter, 1927-1928. (Box 4, Folder 17-18)
    2 folders. Clippings and preservation photocopies.
  - Establishment of paternity avoided in Toledo trial (Nan Britton vs. Charles A. Klunk), 1931. (Box 4, Folder 19)
    Clippings and preservation photocopies.
  - Notices re personal appearance and talk at 55th St. Theatre (with showing of motion picture Children of No Importance]., 1928. (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Notices of bestsellers which included The President's Daughter - Author & daughter in pose (photograph only), 1927-1929. (Box 4, Folder 21-28)
    8 folders. Clippings and preservation photocopies.
  - Material re Nan Britton vs. Charles A. Klunk, 1928-1931. (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Folder 1 of 7. Clippings and preservation copies. Includes letters from Nan Britton to the St. Louis Post Dispatch, August 6, 1928 and to the Buffalo Times, August 7, 1928.
  - Material re Nan Britton vs. Charles A. Klunk, 1928-1931. (Box 5, Folder 2-7)
    Folders 2 through 7 of 7. Clippings and preservation photocopies.
  - Publicity acquired by Judge Grant E. Mouser, 1927-1928. (Box 5, Folder 8-16)
    9 folders. Clippings and preservation photocopies.
  - Reviews of A Dead President Makes Answer, 1928. (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence re Wightman suit, including copy of statement by Richard Wightman, 1927-1928.; 4 folders. (Box 5, Folder 18-21)
  - Material relating to Warren G. Harding's inauguration and death, 1921-1930. (Box 6, Folder 1-4)
    4 folders. Clippings and preservation photocopies.
  - Marion Daily Star, July 6, 1920. (Box 6, Folder 5)
    Preservation photocopy.
  - Marion Daily Star, July 6, 1920. (Box 6, Folder 6)
    Original issue.
  - Marion Daily Star, July 22, 1920. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Marion Daily Star, July 22, 1920. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - New York Herald Tribune, February 15, 1931. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - New York Herald Tribune, February 15, 1931. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Standard Star, New Rochelle, November 21, 1931. (Box 6, Folder 11)
    Preservation photocoopy.
  - Standard Star, New Rochelle, November 21, 1931. (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Review of Reviews, September 1923. (Box 6, Folder 13)
    Containing Harding, Man and President by Judson C. Welliver.
  - Beautiful Ohio, vol.2 no.3, 1960. (Box 6, Folder 13)
    re Marion, Ohio.
  - The Bystander, no.1396 vol.107, September 17, 1930. (Box 6, Folder 13)
    re The President's Daughter.
  - Nation-Wide Review, December 1927. (Box 6, Folder 13)
    re Nan Britton.
  - The New Yorker, October 22, 1927. (Box 6, Folder 14)
    See pp.14 and 102.
  - Confidential Love Secrets, January-February 1956. (Box 6, Folder 14)
    re President Harding's Tragic Love Affair by Kit Carroll.
  - The Junior League Magazine, October 1927. (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Haldeman-Julius Monthly, June 1928. (Box 6, Folder 14)
    Interview with Nan Britton and Elizabeth Ann Harding.
  - The New Republic, September 28, 1927. (Box 6, Folder 14)
    Review of The President's Daughter.
  - Newspaper articles relating to the dedication of the Harding Memorial, 1931. (Box 6, Folder 15-17)
    3 folders. Clippings and preservation photocopies.
  - Material re Charles Forbes after his release from Leavenworth penitentiary, 1927. (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Material re John S. Sumner raid to seize printing plates for The President's Daughter, 1927. (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Material re U.S. Post Office and Department of Justice Investigations into Elizabeth Ann League, 1927. (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Material re proposed libel bill and Nan Britton's position, 1927-1928. (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Material re Representative John N. Tillman's characterization of The President's Daughter before Congress, 1928. (Box 6, Folder 22)
    Clippings and preservation copies.
  - Marion Daily Star, July 5, 1922. (Box 7, Folder 1-4)
    4 folders. Centennial issue. Box 7 is an oversize flat box, 15 × 19.
  - Various newspapers regarding the death of President Harding, 1923. (Box 7, Folder 5-6)
  - Material re screen rights to The President's Daughter, 1927-1928. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Clippings re 3 books about Harding, 1927-1929. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    The Inside Story of the Harding Tragedy, by Harry M. Daugherty, Revelry, by Samuel H. Adams, The Whispering Gallery, by an English Ex-Diplomat. With preservation photocopies.
  - Humorous (?) clippings re The President's Daughter., 1928. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Material re The Strange Death of President Harding, by May Dixon Thacker, 1930-1931. (Box 8, Folder 4-6)
  - Material re Teapot Dome, 1928, 1964. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Publicity resulting from the discovery of the Phillips letters., 1931, 1946, 1964. (Box 8, Folder 8)
    Clippings with preservation photocopies.
  - Reviews and comments on Honesty or Politics by Nan Britton, 1932. (Box 8, Folder 9-11)
  - Suits brought against the Elizabeth Ann Guild, 1927. (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous clippings, v.d. (Box 8, Folder 13-14)
    2 folders. With preservation photocopies.
  - Nan Britton's Harding scrapbook, 1920-1923. (Box 18, Folder 1)
    With photographs, clippings, campaign literature, campaign buttons. Fragile. Box 18 is an oversize flat box, 15.5 × 19.5.